CHRISTOPHER ELLIS

Location: Salt Lake City, UT 84109

Phone: 385-421-0733 | **Email:** christopher.ryan.ellis@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-ellis-b018a67/

GitHub: https://github.com/Arnette110 | Portfolio: https://arnette110.github.io/React-Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in customer service and experience in database management and business operations. Reliable and successful in setting priorities and meeting deadlines. Detail oriented, with devotion to accuracy and efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Applications: Microsoft & Mac platforms, VSCode, GitBash, Heroku, MySQL Workbench, Robo-3T
- Languages/Frameworks/Libraries: MongoDB/mongoose, Express.js, Node.js, React.js, HTML5, CSS3/Bootstrap/Bulma, JavaScript/jQuery, AJAX/Axios, handlebars.js, MySQL/Sequelize

EDUCATION

• Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

A 24-week intensive, Full Stack Web Development, program focused on gaining technical programming skills in MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, MySQL and handlebars.js

• Bachelor of Arts Degree

University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

A degree in the field of International Studies with an emphasis on the study of International Business and German Linguistics

• Undergraduate Coursework

Christian Albrechts Universität zu Kiel, Kiel, Schleswig-Holstein, Germany

Undergraduate summer study in German linguistics and culture

RECENT PROJECTS

Trade & Play

GitHub: https://github.com/Arnette110/Trade-and-Play | Deployed: https://trade-and-play.herokuapp.com/

- A full stack React app for collecting trading cards
- Responsible for the final layout and design as well as nesting components
- o Implemented search functionality in collection dashboard
- Built with Mongo/mongoose, Express.js, Node.js, React.js, Axios, Material-UI, passport.js, Heroku

Stock Watcher!

GitHub: https://github.com/Arnette110/stock-shares-viewer | Deployed: https://guiet-scrubland-40925.herokuapp.com/

- o This is a stock watchlist building app created under the MVC paradigm
- o Responsible for the final layout and design
- Integrated CanvasJS for displaying JSON data as a candlestick chart
- o Assisted in setting up API routes to the database
- Created with Node.js, Express.js, MySQL/Sequelize, AJAX/Axios, CanvasJS, popupS.js, HTML, Bulma, JavaScript/jQuery, Heroku

Employee DireActory

GitHub: https://github.com/Arnette110/Employee-DireActory | Deployed: https://arnette110.github.io/Employee-DireActory/

- $\circ \quad \text{A dynamically updated employee directory table} \\$
- o Responsible for all aspects of the project
- Developed with React/JSX, Bulma, JavaScript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Tire/Alignment Technician

Foothill Tire Pros | March 2018 - Current

- o **Accomplishments:** Successfully trained three new employees
- o Coordinates with team members to ensure efficiency and accuracy of work
- o Executes all aspects of changing tires on customer vehicles
- Performs alignment adjustments

Tele-Underwriter

Equitable Life and Casualty | April 2015 - December 2016

- Accomplishments: Assisted QA department with usability testing of new software, Awarded Employee of the Week Award for outstanding performance and service multiple times
- o Completed medical underwriting interviews with insurance applicants; inbound and outbound calls
- o Provided assistance and guidance to Agents and Co-workers with underwriting inquiries

Client Manager

Chartlogic, Inc | June 2013 - February 2015

- o Educated clients on the effective use of Chartlogic software
- o Proactively reached out to clients to resolve software challenges and create prompt resolution plans
- Fielded incoming support calls; actively listened to client concerns
- Conducted usability testing for software updates